Inventory of the Fulton Bag and Cotton Mills records 1872-1994 MS004
Archives & Records Management, Library and Information Center, Georgia Institute of Technology
- Fulton Bag and Cotton Mills - Materials from Emory University, 1872-1994 (bulk 1881-1956).; SERIES 4; 6.0 Linear feet; (eighteen document cases/oversize boxes)
  - Ledgers, 1881-1958.; SERIES 4, Subseries 2; 3.6 Linear feet; (twenty-five ledgers)
    - MS004-L285: Minutes, Executive Committee, Atlanta, May 1929-November 1943 (Box 32)
    - MS004-L286: Minutes, Executive Committee, Birmingham, January 1918-November 1958 (Box 26)
    - MS004-L287: Minutes, Stockholders, Janurary 1900-January 1947 (Box 27)
  - Scrapbooks, 1881-1956.; SERIES 4, Subseries 3; 2.0 Linear feet; (two scrapbooks and loose materials)
    Subseries 3 is made up of two scrapbooks containing newspaper clippings, some photographs, and many other materials that trace the company's history from its earliest days until about 1956. The first scrapbook, which covers the period from about 1881 to 1949, includes diverse materials such as price lists, sample letterheads from various periods in the company's history, newsletters, biographical information on the founder Jacob Elsas, newspaper clippings, and correspondence. An 1881 inventory partially written in German and written by Hermann Elsas, notices of shares in the company, annual financial statements, and city business licenses are among the earliest documents included here. Loose materials from this scrapbook include a biographical play on the life of Jacob Elsas titled The Master Builder, an obituary of Jacob Elsas, an undated index to the private files of some of the company's leaders, and a 1945 article on the seventy-fifth anniversary of the company. The second of the two scrapbooks includes mainly newspaper clippings from the early 1950s; obituaries for Benjamin Elsas are contained in the loose materials.
    - Scrapbook 1, 1881-1949 (Box 35)
    - Scrapbook 2, 1951-1956 (Box 35)